

Pritiranjan Maharana

Web Developer & Designer

Education

2014 - 2016

BTech - 7.76 C.G.P.A Gandhi Institute of Technological Advancement

2010 - 2012

BSC - 68%

Gonasika Junior Science college

2000 - 2010

HSCE - 81%

Sri Aurobindo Institute of Integral Education

Contact

Phone

+91 8700 1214 83

Email

pritiranjan101@yahoo.com

Address

Omm Bihar,Dhangarapada Keonjhar/Odisha, 758001

Profile

A programmer by mind , a designer from heart. In the quest to understand life, I discovered symmetry between code and design.I love to code and the structure that built it. Passionate about turning abstract ideas into meaningful digital experiences.

Experience

April 2023 - Present

SPARC Pvt. Ltd. (Enrolled with

Mapscope Pvt. Itd.)

UI/UX Developer | Graphic Designer

From concept and prototyping to delivering initial code for user-focused

solutions.

June 2022 - April 2023

Indoplus Private

Limited

Web Developer

Building in-house projects for AP-Group and delivering solutions for external

clients.

Jan 2021 - June 2022

Web Designer / Developer

Reach Digitally Worked for over 2.5 years at Reach

Digitally, handling creative and visual

design projects.

Feb 2018 - July 2019

Shilabs Private Ltd.

Graphics & UX Designer

Served as a Graphic Designer at Shilabs Pvt. Ltd. for approximately 1.5 years,

focusing on creative visual content.

Awards

Poster Presentation

Photography Award: Awarded in Senior category during "Drishtiraaga-2014" on theme "People" Best Poster Award: By Computer Society of India /2015, at Regional Student

Convention, Region - IV

Projects

I've contributed to in my current role

SPARC PVT. Ltd. 2023 - Present

Automation of AIR Quality Monitoring System For Sterling IAQ Consultants

Tech stack : Web based Monitoring System, Smart Report Generation | ReactJS, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL

Developed a modernized UI for Sterling IAQ Consultants' web application, enhancing user experience and operational efficiency. Prototyped designs in Figma and implemented them using React.js, incorporating intuitive navigation, data validation, and visualization tools to improve report generation and client interaction.

LAMS (Land Acquisition Management System)

Tech stack : Web and Mobile based Monitoring System, Smart Report Generation | ReactJS, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, OpenLayer Maps

Contributed to Design and prototype the Land Acquisition Management System, then developed the basic frontend using React.js. Implemented a map view feature to display layers, filter project areas, and manage related functionalities for enhanced visualization and interaction.

Forest Plantation Planning and Monitoring System By CAMPA (Compensatory Afforestation Fund Management and Planning Authority)

Tech stack: Web based Monitoring System, Smart Report Generation | PHP, PostgreSQL, OpenLayer Maps

Designed and prototyped the concept, followed by basic development using PHP. Implemented a map view feature for visualizing plantation areas with split-screen views of pits and plantation plants for better monitoring and planning.

I Minestracker (mining management application)

Tech stack: Web and Mobile based Monitoring System, Smart Report Generation | ReactJS, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, OpenLayer Maps

Conceptualized and prototyped the Minestracker mining management application (SaaS) for both mobile and web, then developed the basic frontend using React.js, ensuring a functional and user-friendly interface.

PRITIRANJAN MAHARANA

Possess comprehensive
expertise across multiple
disciplines in website development and maintenance,
including web graphic
design, user interface (UI)
design, web authoring with
standardized code and
proprietary tools, as well as
search engine optimization
(SEO)

Contact

Omm Bihar,Dhangarapada Keonjhar/Odisha, 758001 +91 870 0121 483

pritiranjan101@yahoo.com

0

pritiranjan__



pritiranjan1001



www.github.com/pritiranjan1001

Design and Code Skills

| _ | HTML | — | PHP | _ | c/c++ |
|---|------------|---|---------|---|-------|
| — | CSS | — | ReactJS | — | NodeJ |
| _ | Javascript | _ | MySQL | _ | Java |

Projects

MOOVIE: Movie Search Portal https://pritiranjan1001.github.io/moovie

 A ReactJs based movie searching app displaying the movie details and videos. Designed with HTML, CSS, REACTJS. Used TMDB third party APIs.

Traveller: A social Travel webportal www.github.com/pritiranjan1001/traveller

 Php (Laravel) based web application where a user can register and share the places, photos and videos.

StoryBoard : A Writer's Portal

www.github.com/pritiranjan1001/storyboard

 StoryBoard is a web application based on writer's blog. A writer can create his/her own account and display their work with the community.

Kwalks: A Social Media Web app www.github.com/pritiranjan1001/kwalks

 This is a Core php based web portal for social media purposes. Used SHA15 as encryption and bootstrap CSS framework.

UI / UX Mockups

https://pritiranjan1001.github.io/highlights

UI/UX mock-ups website of different clients.
 Initially designed with photoshop and then converted in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Hello! I'm Pritiranjan Graphic Designer & UI/UX Designer

+91 870 012 1483
Omm Bihar, Dhangarapada,
Keonjhar, Odisha, 758001
pritiranjanmaharana53@gmail.com
https://pritiranjan1001.github.io/mywb

Art and Illustrations

Digital Art

Photoshop/Illustrator

Art Design through Graphic Software which turns into Digital Form.

Sketches and Story boarding paper/canvas/photoshop It includes Charcoal Art ,Pencil art etc.

Painting

canvas/paper/photoshop

Creative Aryclic Paintings, Grafity, Potrait Art, Landscape etc.

Skills & Expertise

Typography
Color Theory

Layout Design

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe After Effects

Adobe Premier Pro

Figma

Work Experience

As a Graphics Designer

https://pritiranjan1001.github.io/highlights/portfolio-min.pdf

More than 4yr as a Graphics Designer and Creative Artist involved in many projects from Brand Design, Web Mockup, Logo Design, Booklet, Social Media Posts, Art and Illustration, Cover Design, Character Design etc.

As a Photographer

https://pritiranjan1001.github.io/mywb/image-show.html

I have experience in Digital Photography in the area of Wild Life, Landscape , Street Photography and Product Photography.

As a Video Editor

https://youtu.be/NWUIpL89V94

Done some Music Videos, Promotion Videos, Motion Graphics, Short Story video Editing in freelance basics.